FIONA FREEMARK

FINE TO A A DIZ fiona.freemark@gmail.

fiona.freemark@gmail.com toronto, canada

portfolio | github | linked in | schedule chat

416 500 6874

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

CAREER PROFILE

Front-end developer with 11 years of experience in the arts, bringing a unique blend of creative and technical skills to the tech world. Passion for building accessible & responsive code, matched by keen eye for design and attention to detail. Creative problem-solver and motivated team player.

Open to in-office, hybrid, and remote positions.

SKILLS

Technical: React, JavaScript (ES6+), HTML, CSS, SCSS, Git, REST APIs, Firebase, Accessibility, Responsive Design, Figma, Lightroom, Photoshop, Squarespace, Format, Mailchimp, Blogger

Transferable: Creative Problem-Solving, Detail-Oriented, Time Management, Analytical, Customer Service

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology - Toronto

Immersive Web Development Bootcamp, Certificate 2022 - 2023
Intro to Web Development 2021

McMaster University - Hamilton

B.A. Honours Studio Art with Distinction 2008 - 2012

SELECT PROJECTS

<u>Jobi Job Board</u>
LIVE | REPO

React | JavaScript | Sass | HTML

Job board app for employers to post available positions to prospective employees. PSD conversion built within 10 days as part of a design sprint.

Whatever Floats Your Vote

<u>LIVE | REPO</u>

React | JavaScript | Firebase | Sass | HTML

Anonymous voting application built with React, JavaScript and Firebase that allows users to create, find, vote on, and view poll results. Accessible & responsive.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Website + Social Media Coordinator / Administrator - Dianna Witte Gallery - Toronto

2012 - Present

- Led redesign of website using Squarespace. Improved user experience, SEO rankings.
- Maintained domain/email hosting through GoDaddy/Mecca. Created Google Workspace accounts to streamline emails/document sharing. Device bluetooth/wifi troubleshooting.
- Increased gallery audience by developing a strong social media presence on Instagram (0 to 7000+ followers) & email campaigns using Mailchimp/Squarespace.
- Completed training program to improve online marketing. Implemented techniques (calls-to-action/posting schedule) across website & social media.
- Organized numerous projects annually (exhibitions & off-site projects). Worked directly with up to 25 artists to develop press releases, consignment agreements and online presentations of works.

Artist - Self-Employed - Toronto

2012 - Present

- Initiated development & creation of projects from brainstorming to research, production, mounting and presentation.
- Awarded Exhibition Assistance grant by the Ontario Arts Council for solo show of photo-based artwork in May of 2022 as Core Exhibition of the Scotiabank CONTACT Photography Festival.
- Customized portfolio website with e-commerce feature using Format.

Header Framer / Assistant Framer - Deserres - Toronto

2017 - 2022 / 2014 - 2017

- Designed framing solutions through collaboration & attention to preferences/budgets (ranges up to \$2000).
- Proven time management, often delivering projects in advance of deadline.
- Improved organization, training & communication for framing staff (ex. created reference materials).
- Trained 3 consultants on procedures and best practices in designing, art handling and framing.
- Collaborated with other framing departments to problem solve & share production responsibilities when required.